<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Yiluan Song&#39;s teaching website</title>
    <link>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Yiluan Song&#39;s teaching website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GitHub</title>
      <link>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/2023/09/10/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/2023/09/10/github/</guid>
      <description>This is a practical introduction to using Git and GitHub.
Guest lectures in UCSC ENVS 280 Data Science for the Environment and UofM IGCB R Session.
Objectives Know the importance and rationale of version control and Git Learn some basic commands in Git Set up a GitHub account and your project Play with branch and fork Version control What is &amp;ldquo;version control,&amp;rdquo; and why should you care? Version control is a system that records changes to a file or set of files over time so that you can recall specific versions later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phenology sample data</title>
      <link>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/2023/09/10/phenology-sample-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/2023/09/10/phenology-sample-data/</guid>
      <description>Data prepared for Dr. Yang Chen’s class STATS605 in 2023 Fall, also good for others interested in exploring phenology data.
Data files and code for generating them can be found in this GitHub repo.
This blog gives some first steps reading and visualizing the data.
Meta data for trees metadata &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;data/metadata.csv&amp;quot;) metadata %&amp;gt;% head() %&amp;gt;% flextable::regulartable() %&amp;gt;% flextable::autofit() %&amp;gt;% flextable::fit_to_width(8) (#tab:unnamed-chunk-2)Part of the meta data for tagged trees. site</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogdown</title>
      <link>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/2023/09/09/blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/2023/09/09/blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Read blogdown instructions here.
Set up a blogdown project Create an R project. It is strongly recommended to make the working directory a GitHub repo for version control and deployment.
Make this folder a blogdown site using R package blogdown.
install.packages(&amp;quot;blogdown&amp;quot;) blogdown::new_site() HUGO may be installed automatically, but manually install HUGO if necessary. The example below is for windows. See full installation instructions here.
winget install Hugo.Hugo.Extended If the installed HUGO cannot be found, set PATH to include the path for HUGO</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
