<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yiluan Song&#39;s teaching website</title>
    <link>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Yiluan Song&#39;s teaching website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Non-metric Multidimensional Scaling (NMDS)</title>
      <link>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/2023/10/04/non-metric-multidimensional-scaling-nmds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/2023/10/04/non-metric-multidimensional-scaling-nmds/</guid>
      <description>Guest lecture for Dr. Drew Gronewold&amp;rsquo;s class EAS 501.077 Multivariate Statistics for Environmental Science in 2023 Fall.
Objectives Compare parametric and nonparametric methods for ordination Learn about real-life applications of NMDS Practice using NMDS in R to analyze community composition Get familiar with a statistical test, PERMANOVA Parametric or nonparametric? In previous classes, we have learned about principal component analysis (PCA).
PCA have certain assumptions, requiring the data to be</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible workflow</title>
      <link>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/2023/09/13/reproducible-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/2023/09/13/reproducible-workflow/</guid>
      <description>A research project is computationally reproducible if a second investigator (including you in the future) can recreate the final reported results of the project, including key quantitative findings, tables, and figures, given only a set of files and written instructions.
Kitzes, J., Turek, D., &amp;amp; Deniz, F. (Eds.). (2018). The Practice of Reproducible Research: Case Studies and Lessons from the Data-Intensive Sciences. Oakland, CA: University of California Press. Link to book</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub</title>
      <link>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/2023/09/10/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/2023/09/10/github/</guid>
      <description>This is a practical introduction to using Git and GitHub.
Guest lectures in UCSC ENVS 280 Data Science for the Environment and UofM IGCB R Session.
Objectives Know the importance and rationale of version control and Git Learn some basic commands in Git Set up a GitHub account and your project Play with branch and fork Version control What is &amp;ldquo;version control,&amp;rdquo; and why should you care? Version control is a system that records changes to a file or set of files over time so that you can recall specific versions later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phenology sample data</title>
      <link>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/2023/09/10/phenology-sample-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/2023/09/10/phenology-sample-data/</guid>
      <description>Data prepared for Dr. Yang Chen’s class STATS605 in 2023 Fall, also good for others interested in exploring phenology data.
Data files and code for generating them can be found in this GitHub repo.
This blog gives some first steps reading and visualizing the data.
Meta data for trees metadata &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;data/metadata.csv&amp;quot;) metadata %&amp;gt;% head() %&amp;gt;% flextable::regulartable() %&amp;gt;% flextable::autofit() %&amp;gt;% flextable::fit_to_width(8) (#tab:unnamed-chunk-2)Part of the meta data for tagged trees. site</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogdown</title>
      <link>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/2023/09/09/blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/2023/09/09/blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Read blogdown instructions here.
Set up a blogdown project Create an R project. It is strongly recommended to make the working directory a GitHub repo for version control and deployment.
Make this folder a blogdown site using R package blogdown.
install.packages(&amp;quot;blogdown&amp;quot;) blogdown::new_site() HUGO may be installed automatically, but manually install HUGO if necessary. The example below is for windows. See full installation instructions here.
winget install Hugo.Hugo.Extended If the installed HUGO cannot be found, set PATH to include the path for HUGO</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiluansong.github.io/teaching/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a website for the Yiluan Song&amp;rsquo;s teaching and documentation.
Dr. Yiluan Song is a postdoctoral researcher at the Michigan Institute for Data Science, supported by the Eric and Wendy Schmidt AI in Science Postdoctoral Fellowship, co-advised by Drs. Kai Zhu and Yang Chen. Yiluan is also affiliated with the Institute for Global Change Biology at the University of Michigan. Yiluan is interested in integrating mechanistic understanding and cutting-edge machine learning methods to study how ecosystems respond to global change drivers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
